[Music]
welcome to busy cental lunch event
related to 2024 release Wave 2 my name
is Alexander toic and today with me I
have my colleague Magnus hi my name is
Magus and I'm a software engineer in
business
Central okay thank you Magnus uh we will
today in explain what is new in
electronic documents show L we will just
explain a few things from a previous
release and what is new in this release
and then we will switch to demo where
Magnus will show you uh setup of
different services and new features we
deliver in this
wave okay before we start I just wanted
to remind you uh how we started e
documents first idea was to start with
invoicing but we decided to switch to e
documents as it can be Central hub for
exchanging any type of electronic
documents when I say any probably not
are really any but the most of
electronic documents can be exchanged
through eents
module uh our main focus is to manage
all incoming and outcoming documents but
current Focus for Microsoft side is
still electronic invoicing exchange so
feature is open for exchanging any of um
as a feature framework is open for
exchanging any type of documents but
Microsoft is currently focus on
electronic voicing uh
all uh upcoming and features in this
release are actually driven by
regulatory requirements and feedback uh
we are getting from Community for
partners and customers but what is
important to remember uh again this
framework is designed to be easy
extendable and allowing all isvs or
other partners to integrate various type
of electronic documents so we are again
open not only for regulatory features we
are open to uh extend the functionality
to make it EAS easier for you to build
on top of
that why electronic invoices primary if
you look in this table you will see
first that b2g uh electronic invoic is
definitely mandatory majority of
countries across the world actually this
is list of localization where Microsoft
deliver localizations not partner based
localization so probably uh this list
will be much much bigger but if you look
in our localization may u support
localization processes b2g is already
mandat but it was not trigger uh for us
to start with electronic documents
electronic invoices B2B mandat being
mandatory was a trigger for us so if you
look right now this is mandatory in
Denmark in Belgium in Italy uh India
Mexico in this moment we already have
Italian and Mexico electronic invoicing
in old format so uh for our future um
backlog this is something what we will
move to New
framework and um outside of these
countries you will see that Australia
New Zealand have recommended uh usage of
B2B so this is not mandatory but this is
highly recommended to
use uh but this yellow column with B2B
voluntary you can see again that this is
available for for voluntary usage in all
these countries so if not mandatory this
is voluntary so you can use you can
automate some of your processes
especially account payable there are a
lot of automation there and you have
when we talk about plans you see these
orange plans in the right columns that
um France Germany and Spain will come
sooner but other countries will come
again in a few years so we decided to
first to be focused on electronic
invoicing so we will be compliant in all
these
regulations okay now let's focus what we
have in this wave first uh we have some
improvements electronic documents
framework so you can see we have new
default end points they will not be
available immediately from this major
release so first will come with
25.1 and others will be deliver in this
period now I cannot see exactly because
um we need to finish reviewing to to
check all these details we need to be
really sure that everything will work as
expected but what I want to um emphasize
here uh majority of these connectors are
uh made in collaboration with these
partners so we use open source
collaboration model and we work together
with a Partners so these Partners made
the majority of these things by themsel
and uh from our side we instructed how
to do it and now we are making a review
of code so code quality must be the same
as Microsoft is delivering so this is
why it cannot be delivered immediately
but you can expect that very soon you
will have all these connectors so
avalara B2B router Contin logic sign up
the the every and through Commerce this
is important so now except pagero as we
already have in total until the end of
this wave we will have eight default
connectors so you can choose what you
want to use again uh you will not have
any commercial model inside the BC so
you must sign contract with these
providers uh but once when you have
contact you can just choose one of these
options and make a setup easy setup you
will see how it easy and you can
continue to work without any additional
development and configuration
then additionally we added one of the
highly uh required feature having
attachments as encoded object uh within
XML files it was important it is
important because XML files with payo
and other f file formats are good for as
a machine readable format so they can be
easily translated from XML to purchase
documents that's good but this is not
easy for human read as a human readable
format so having encoded uh attachment
inside this is something what can
improve a human readable usage so it
will be much easier for users to handle
with electronic documents then we
improve some small things in the search
it was not easy because uh you had to
use Dash or not now this is much easier
to find the all these pag in a search we
also added uh some small things you
cannot recognize on our first side but
we wanted to stabilize this framework it
was our focus on stabilizing so we work
a lot of small features in inside the
framework and you will see e documents
apis first idea was to deliver them in a
major but we decided to postpone because
we got some better idea how we can
improve this API so we wanted to take
some additional time so the most
probably 25.3 we will deliver e
documents API so you can reuse them in a
Bo and purchase and sales process and it
will be really good for you if you want
to integrate then we have another part
it documents localizations as you know
we already have by default P B3 in a W1
so this is available in all localization
and we have Papo deliver as a code and
as a data exchange definition so you can
use this as a showcase how to build your
own formats if you need so you can
choose what is better for you it depends
from country to country from partner to
partner they some of them uh much more
prefer Cod some of them data exchange so
we are open we have good showcase so you
can see how you can make your own format
but from Microsoft side in period from
December this year until the April 25th
we will um deliver this format to be
more accurate uh in December we will
deliver ex and in Germany and fatura a
in Spain so uh this country will be a
compliance uh from the beginning of next
year because it will be mandatory usage
of electronic do electronic invoicing in
in Spain and Germany and P and Z format
for Australia New Zealand will come
after new year so this is by I said
until the April uh
25 okay it was shortly what we have in
this release and now I will give a word
my colleague Magnus so he will show you
how it's look like in a demo thanks
Alexander thanks for introducing the new
features Let's uh see how they look in
business Central so with me today I have
a a GB environment in version 251 so uh
let's uh search for E
documents and here we can see that I
have created a e doent service for
today's demo if we open that up we can
see that the service integration that I
have selected is the new integration
that we have added
avalara and we still have peero as well
uh that you can use and there will be
more to come the next coming months so
if we open up a setup service
integration in order to set up avalara
we can see that we don't actually have
to add a lot of things we have to
provide the client ID and the client SE
secet as well as selecting avalara
Company ID to link your avalara company
ID to your business Central uh company
so let's go ahead and do that we just
click the action and then we select one
of our avalara companies I will select
Ms business
Central and then we also have to select
an avalara mandate which determines uh
when we send our invoices to Avalar this
mandate specifies what checks should be
done to verify uh if the right fields
and so on are provided since we are in a
GB environment and I want to demo a
businessto business scenario with pble
I'm going to find that in the list so GB
B2B pble select that and then that is
what will be used when we send with this
service just to uh compare how it was
with uh pagero I'll switch to another
company where I have the pagero setup
here so you can see it's still very very
similar um the URLs are already filled
out for you you just provide like these
small pieces of information so in pagero
for instance it it is the company ID you
need to provide but with avalara we are
we asking for client ID and client
secret and that's essentially everything
the service is using the pble format and
uh then let's go see how we send an
invoice using it so I'll just go go to
customers I will select the tray
research and as you can
see here we have the document sending
profile set for this customer to e
doents allowing us to actually use the E
doent framework when we post invoices so
let's create a new sales
invoice and from here we will just have
to fill out a couple of things so the
first thing I will fill out is the
reference as that is required by the P
format and then I will sell a let's say
a desk and we will just sell
one and then as Alexander said before
we've also added in the pble format that
we can send uh attachments so I will
also go ahead and actually attach a PDF
here so we will just use this invoice
sample like
so and that is everything we need to
just go ahead and uh post it
and then this will uh take the invoice
create a XML format in Pebble and then
send that to avalara that will then send
it on to the receiving end and we'll see
that in just a
second there we go and then we just uh
open the posted
invoice and then we navigate to the E
doent that has been
created and here we can see that the E
doent is in pending response State and
this is because the way it works with
avalara is that we we send the the
invoice to them then they will do some
processing to with the mandate to verify
that the correct things are provided and
then we will have to actually send
another request to Avalar asking if the
the processing of this invoice was
successful so normally or in production
this is happening in the background
automatically you don't have to do
anything but because we are in a demo
today I will just go ahead and
and Trigger this in our job
tues like
so and now we can see that the document
is indeed sent so this is all you need
to do to uh to send with our allow let's
let's look at it from the other side
which we want to receive so I'm going to
change to a different company uh trade
research and now we want to receive
invoices from our vendors so I'm going
to go to E
doents and here we can see we have
already received documents before um and
then we can open up e doent services
from here and just as with the other
company we have set up a service that is
using the avalara integration one thing
I will add is that you should uh you
should set a to import when you're using
this in production such that every x
amount of time we will run and check if
there is a new incoming documents
because we are again running running at
demo today I will just do this manually
so I will click the receive action to
see if there's anything new and this
will just run for a little bit it says
processing eent so it found one and it
will create the purchase invoice so
let's go back to the
list and from here you can see we got a
new entry we can open that up and we can
see everything is as it should be it's
uh created it says import document
created and we can actually also open
the purchase invoice that we generated
for you and you can see it here and it
also has the
attachment um that we attached when we
send it and that's essentially for
sending and receiving with avalara thank
you Magnus um as you can see this is
something uh what we deliver in this
wave and you can insect some other
connectors and other features uh in X
miners in the meantime call for Action
uh if you didn't start to use electronic
documents earlier we have on YouTube uh
recordings from previous VES so you can
familiarize yourself little bit more in
details of what we have in electronic
documents so because today you could see
only what is new so please watch old
videos to see what we had in the
beginning how it works the total and
then you can easily understand what is
new in this release and how we are
improving this feature okay thank you
for watching us thank you